[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome back to
trien tasa automation
tutorial so this is our lesson
seven where I'm going to teach you how
to identify the controls by using
properties
and by using anchor in tricentis tasa 16
and also how can you create a control
group in TSA
16 please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you okay so what is our
agenda item the first agenda item is I'm
going to teach you how to identify the
controls by using properties the
technical properties of your control and
how can you identify the controls by
specific
property and by using a specific
property is a default identification
method in
tasa okay it's keep in mind that in
generally the tasa identifies all the
controls by using properties by
default and you can use unlimited
unlimited number of properties for
identifying your control so I'm going to
show you how can you use multiple
properties in identifying the
controls and
also use the properties that are
necessary and stable why when you are
identifying a control yes you can
actually use multiple properties n
number of properties in identifying the
object but it's not recommended to use
lot of properties that slows down your
system so better to use necessary and
stable properties
only okay and also I'm going to teach
you how can you identify the controls by
using anchor property okay it's very
useful concept okay generally tasa looks
for an an anchor control first and then
serves the target control in the
relation of the anchor so what do you
mean by anchor control so let's say I
want to identify login button so I'm
going to use a reference of anchor
control probably title of the page or
some other object so I'm going to use
that reference as an anchor property or
anchor control so with that reference of
your anchor control I'm going to
identify the
login link or the login button in the
reference of anchor control okay and
also I'm going to teach you how to
create the control
groups okay so all these Concepts I'm
going to teach
you in this session so now let's jump
onto the system and see how can we
identify the controls by using
properties and by using anchor
method okay so this is my uh latest
version of tasar okay so and I'm
actually navigated to mod section okay
so I explained about all these sections
in my previous videos I would recommend
you guys to visit my previous videos
okay so I'm in module section now let's
what is our first agenda is identifying
the controls by using properties okay
let's see okay right click on modules
click on scan and select application
scan
okay once you select application scan
it's going to show you all the
applications that are open in your
desktop
okay yeah so these are all the
applications I need demo webshop and
then click on
scan okay so we are as soon as you click
on scan right now I'm in advanced view
okay this is my basic view I already
explained about all these Advanced and
basic views and then what is our xcan
right um so I would recommend you guys
to go through my previous video okay so
here now I would like to add all my this
product tabs okay I would like
to capture the controls of my product
tabs okay let's see how can we do
okay there are two ways either I can use
select on screen method okay let's are I
can directly go to basic View and then
keep clicking on these objects that will
add all the objects see
third fourth menu fifth menu sixth menu
seventh menu okay I think this is
something different okay okay so these
are all
the controls that I have added now I
would like to go for the advanced View
okay so where are the controls that we
added so if you scroll
down yeah these are the controls that we
added correct so and one more thing is
if You
observe okay let me see
okay so when I click on this
control let me also do one thing okay
let me also do one
thing yeah okay so if you see on the
page you have books this way and there
is another categories right categories
where you have again books computers
Electronics appar right categories and
the product tabs okay so let's
assume let's now if I see the categories
okay and this is let's select this as
well so if you see the product called
the the product categories books is the
selected item is not
uniquely identified not unique that
means this particular
books control the technical properties
are matching with some other control
technical properties so that's why this
books category is not identified
uniquely okay so to make it uniquely
identified
you can do one thing you can actually
select multiple technical properties
let's assume I want to add another
technical property called
visible as soon as I select visible see
at the bottom okay see at the
bottom left corner now the selected item
is not unique as soon as I select a
technical property called visible then
the object will convert the notification
turns into uniquely identified see at
the bottom okay I'm clicking on this
visible right side visible
property done see if you see here the
selected item is
unique okay this is the way you can
uniquely identify your controls by using
technical properties so that means I
have almost added one two three tag
inner text and visible so three
properties to identify an object object
or control as a unique okay so that
means you can use n number of technical
properties to make a control identified
uniquely okay and let me tell you one
more thing so this on top here right
demo webshop login if you
see this is the title what is the title
of this demo webshop login the title is
let me show you the title is demo
webshop not login if I go to register
then the title will change to register
what demoe shop. register if I click on
shopping cart then the title will change
to title of the page will change to demo
webshop
docot okay so that means the title keeps
changing based on the page where you
landed correct right so to handle this
this particular object or control I need
to change the property called title how
should I change I should change the
property as see here instead of
login I can simply put a
star as a regular expression that means
any page will start with demo webshop
title and it might have some text
okay so let me just uh because we
already changed the page right let me
rescan okay I need to rescan again okay
scan let's go to advaned view okay so
I'm talking about this right this page
see
here I Chang I remoted it I kept star
and
then that's it that means I can uniquely
identify the page title like this and
now what we added actually the all the
products let's add all the products
again okay I'm directly I I can add all
the product menu items directly from
here also this is also another way
okay this is another way okay so so
let's see these are all uniquely
identified okay now let's you can
actually the module name you can change
the module name I want to change this
as demo
webshop demo web
Shop
product tabs because I'm storing all the
product tab links that's why I'm
naming this module as product tabs okay
done now you can simply finish screen
that will create a module I explained
you about this in earlier session also
so now if you see see we have now
created demo webshop product tabs and if
you expand this you have all the
controls that
we captured while doing the xcan
okay so this way identifying the
controls by using multiple Properties or
by using any kind of technical
properties okay so what is our next
agenda next agenda is identify the
properties by using anchor okay so let's
again let me do one thing let me create
a new module Okay click on modules so
let's first uh okay yeah let's be on the
same page right
click
scan
application and
then and
then let me do one thing right click
scan application oh sorry let me first
close the scanner here okay we already
opened one scanner so right click click
on scan and
application okay so now you need to
select the application as usual
okay so this is demo webshop click on
scan and now I want to add the
categories okay instead of this I want
to add the categories okay let's go back
to your basic
View and then add
books add computers Electronics apparel
and choose download gelry and gift card
if you see here let's go back to
Advanced also because if you see in the
orange color that means these objects
are not uniquely identified see the
selected is not unique the selected item
is not unique okay so let's go back to
Advanced view okay first okay because
all these are highlighted in orange
color that means these objects are not
uniquely
identified okay now I want to resolve
this issue by using anchor okay I want
to identify this books
all these controls by using identify by
anchor if you see on the top identify
by click on anchor so first of all you
need to select the control you need to
select the control that you would like
to identify by the anchor okay I clicked
on this control and then identify by
anchor as soon as you click on identify
by anchor the right side the ident ify
by anchor pain will be opening okay and
before you do that I need to see some
more elements that are not visible on
this page like div UL right or any hre
tags right all these kind of technical
properties I would like to see how can
we do that you need to use the filter
here you have to expand the filter in a
such a way that it shows you see now
apart from books whatever the links that
you are watching on the screen it shows
more technical properties okay so if you
see the books computers all these links
are under the container called UL under
the container called UL so I would like
to use this container as my anchor to
identify these links
uniquely okay for that time what I'm
going to do again first let's do books I
would like to identify books as an uh
unique control by using anchor okay
right click sorry identify by
anchor and now you need to select the
anchor that you would like to use in
related to Books Okay so this is my
anchor right click on this anchor drag
and drop the anchor here right side if
you see on the right right side pan drag
and drop the anchor here and if You
observe clearly when I drag and drop the
anchor it says the anchor control is not
uniquely identified see to identify any
control by
anchored first of all the anchor should
be you clear identified okay so if you
see there is an option to make
anchor unique if you see at the bottom
there is a button make anchor unique or
I can directly select class name so that
it makes unique anchor okay let's
see let's the make let's make anchor
unique so as soon as I click on this
make anchor unique what it did it
selected inner HTML and if you see at
the bottom now the selected item is
unique that means now the anchor is
unique okay and if you see the books
also now turned onto gray color that
means this is unique what about
computers now again computers you have
to do same thing
right again computers you have to do
same thing identify by anchor click on
anchor drag ul and drop
here and done this is also unique letter
identified now go to
electronics identify
anchor drag U container as your anchor
that's it apparal and shoes identify by
anchor drag the anchor
control then digital download identify
by anchor track the UL container as an
anchor
control so digital download are uniquely
identified now
jewelry identify by anchor drag the
anchor control here done now gift cards
right last
one drag the UL control as an anchor
control done so now I can see all the
product
categories are now uniquely
identified and let me explain one more
thing see in the anchor control if you
see here what kind of relative algorithm
that tasa would like to consider in
identifying all these categories that
also you can Define there are three
three types One is using the relative
algorithm called Auto or shortest path
or
coordinate so Auto when you select auto
it actually by default TSA will use the
shortest path okay if shortest path is
not worked out then it uses coordinate
okay that is auto what is shortest path
what shortest path is first in the tree
structure in the tree of your
HTML uh design right it starts
identifying the object or the
control from the anchor control okay
first it's searches for the anchor
control and then from anchor control in
the tree structure it start identifying
your corresponding object or
corresponding control in related with
the anchor control okay if you use
coordinate right what it will do it
actually uses the coordinates to
identify your
control but this coordinates if you
select these coordinates what happens if
the screen resolution is Chang then
there might be big chances that the
control might not be able to find okay
so better you select auto or shortest
path okay so for all these controls I'm
identifying the
controls by
anchor by using relative algorithm as
Auto okay so once these controls are
selected and one more thing is see you
need not to okay so I want to add all
these controls you need not to add this
what I can say the container right so
that's why I don't want to I don't want
to select this container
okay okay I think again it's all got
Disturbed let me just again identify by
anchor and
then okay yeah yeah so now all are
actually uniquely identified now what I
can do I can save this let me save
before this I want to rename this as
demo
webshop this time
product
categories okay product categories
because I'm saving all the links related
to product categories okay and then
click on finish
screen so what happens it's going to
create and let's close the xcan it's
going to create another module if you
see here see the new module called
Product categories these are all we
added by using anchor controls correct
done now what is our next agenda how can
you create the control groups okay what
do you mean by control groups control
groups are if you want
to group all the controls based on the
type of control let's say I want to
group all the
links as one C uh control group I want
to
um group all the buttons as one control
group I want to group all text boxes as
one control group okay you can do that
how let's say these are all actually
links right I can simply what links
product category links I can
simply select all these
controls and then right click and click
on convert to control
group what is the
control group you can just rename this
control group
as
product
C
categories links right so if you expand
this now so all
these controls are actually part of
product categories links so this way you
can group all of your controls based on
the type I mean whatever the way you
want okay or if you want to again remove
this control group right click and
convert to separate X module attributes
if you click on this again now all these
are will be separated as normal
controls these are not grouped right
okay hope you all understand the
concepts of identify controls by
properties and as I explained you
identify controls by specific properties
a default identification method in Taska
and also I showed you how can we use the
properties multiple properties and
identifying
the control and also user properties
that are necessary and stable so
basically
um using properties are necessary and
stable so basically we need to use the
properties sir sorry so there is a spell
mistake okay we need to use the
properties that are necessary and stable
you need not to use n a number of
properties because using multiple more
properties takes uh more time in
identifying the controls okay and also I
showed you how to identify controls by
anchor correct and also I showed you how
to create control groups okay hope you
all understand the concepts if you have
any queries provide your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond thank
you
[Music]